Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
=The Palace Gambit=
=مناورة القصر=
= Episode 14 =
= الحلقة 14 =
(We'll Meet Again In The Next Life)
(سنلتقي مرة أخرى في الحياة القادمة)
Please investigate!
يرجى التحقيق!
You said that I'm manipulated.
لقد قلت أنني متلاعب.
Then I'd like to ask
ثم أود أن أسأل
who is manipulating me.
من يتلاعب بي؟
I long to conceive a royal heir
أتوق إلى إنجاب وريث ملكي
for His Majesty.
لجلالته.
But when no such blessing exists,
ولكن عندما لا توجد مثل هذه النعمة،
I would never dare fabricate such a falsehood.
لن أجرؤ أبدًا على اختلاق مثل هذه الكذبة.
Clearly, Lady Shen is scared of Consort Chun
من الواضح أن السيدة شين خائفة من الزوجة تشون
and too threatened
وهددت كثيرا
to speak.
للتحدث.
They're colluding with the physician
إنهم يتواطؤون مع الطبيب
to deceive everyone.
لخداع الجميع.
Miss Jiuning,
الآنسة جيونينج،
you mustn't make baseless accusations!
لا يجوز لك توجيه إتهامات لا أساس لها!
You said
أنت قلت
that I bribed the imperial physician
أنني رشوت الطبيب الإمبراطوري
and manipulated Lady Shen.
وتلاعب بالسيدة شين.
Where is your proof?
أين دليلك؟
You can't possibly slander me
لا يمكنك أن تقذفني
without a shred of evidence!
بدون ذرة من الأدلة!
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
I beg you to summon another physician for re-examination.
أرجو منك استدعاء طبيب آخر لإعادة الفحص.
I stake my life on this.
أنا أراهن بحياتي على هذا.
Lady Shen is truly pregnant.
السيدة شين حامل حقا.
This concerns the royal heir.
وهذا يتعلق بالوريث الملكي.
Please reconsider.
يرجى إعادة النظر.
Noble Consort Xian, you know medicine well
السيدة النبيلة شيان، أنت تعرفين الطب جيدًا
and can read pulses.
ويمكنه قراءة النبضات.
Go examine Lady Shen.
اذهب لفحص السيدة شين.
Yes,
نعم،
Your Majesty.
جلالتك.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
Lady Shen
السيدة شين
shows no signs of pregnancy.
لا يظهر أي علامات الحمل.
How is this possible?
كيف هذا ممكن؟
Jiuning,
جيونينج،
you disgraced yourself.
لقد أهنت نفسك.
Beg for mercy at once.
اطلب الرحمة على الفور.
I know I was wrong.
أعلم أنني كنت مخطئا.
I beg your forgiveness.
أطلب منك السماح.
Noble Consort Xian,
الزوجة النبيلة شيان،
a maid from your palace dared accuse without evidence
لقد تجرأت خادمة من قصرك على الإتهام دون دليل
before the entire court
أمام المحكمة بأكملها
that I bribed the imperial physician
أنني رشوت الطبيب الإمبراطوري
and manipulated Lady Shen.
وتلاعب بالسيدة شين.
Did you train her to be this audacious?
هل درّبتها لتكون جريئة إلى هذه الدرجة؟
Or did she act recklessly
أم أنها تصرفت بتهور؟
because you shielded her?
لأنك قمت بحمايتها؟
She's turned this Dragon Boat banquet into chaos.
لقد حولت وليمة قوارب التنين هذه إلى فوضى.
Is this how
هل هذه هي الطريقة
you normally instruct your maids
عادة ما تقومين بتوجيه الخادمات لديك
to disregard law and order,
تجاهل القانون والنظام،
acting without restraint?
التصرف دون ضبط النفس؟
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
I've failed in disciplining.
لقد فشلت في التأديب.
I willingly accept punishment.
أقبل العقاب طوعا.
Noble Consort Xian has shown incompetent governance.
لقد أظهرت الزوجة النبيلة شيان حكمًا غير كفء.
Revoke Phoenix Seal.
إلغاء ختم فينيكس.
She's confined to Yongxiu Palace for self-reflection.
لقد تم حجزها في قصر يونغشيو للتأمل الذاتي.
All Yongxiu Palace staff forfeit a year's wages.
جميع موظفي قصر يونغشيو يتنازلون عن أجور عام كامل.
Yongxiu Palace maid Lu Jiuning,
خادمة قصر يونغ شيو لو جيونينغ،
for slandering consorts
لتشويه سمعة الزوجات
and insubordination, shall get 50 strikes.
والعصيان يعاقب بخمسين ضربة.
Guards!
حراس!
Take her away!
خذها بعيدا!
- Yes!
- نعم!
Now that you understand the truth,
الآن بعد أن فهمت الحقيقة،
don't be foolish.
لا تكن أحمقا.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
I'd never dare deceive you.
لن أجرؤ على خداعك أبدًا.
Last night,
ليلة أمس،
Lu Jiuning
لو جيونينج
planned for me to eat greasy food
لقد خططت لتناول طعام دهني
to induce vomiting
للحث على التقيؤ
at the Dragon Boat banquet,
في مأدبة قوارب التنين،
and then have the attending physician
ومن ثم يجب عليك استشارة الطبيب المعالج
declare my pregnancy.
أعلن عن حملي.
Lu Jiuning
لو جيونينج
schemed against me with elaborate cunning.
لقد خططوا ضدي بمكر متقن.
Chief Physician Zhang.
الطبيب الرئيسي تشانغ.
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي، صاحب السمو.
Your Highness, what are you doing?
صاحب السمو ماذا تفعل؟
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
Lady Shen,
السيدة شين،
there's no need for fear.
لا داعي للخوف .
This silver needle will pierce your maihui acupoint.
هذه الإبرة الفضية سوف تخترق نقطة الوخز بالإبر الخاصة بك.
Once embedded,
بمجرد تضمينها،
it suppresses pregnancy pulses,
فهو يثبط نبضات الحمل،
making them undetectable.
جعلها غير قابلة للكشف.
No physician could diagnose
لم يتمكن أي طبيب من تشخيص
your condition accurately.
حالتك بدقة.
Lady Shen,
السيدة شين،
don't worry.
لا تقلق.
You just follow Lu Jiuning's instructions.
ما عليك سوى اتباع تعليمات لو جيونينج.
I'll turn her scheme against her
سأحول مخططها ضدها
and uproot Yongxiu Palace completely.
وإزالة قصر يونغشيو بالكامل.
The Empress Dowager has arrived.
لقد وصلت الإمبراطورة الأرملة.
- Long life and health to Your Majesty.
- طول العمر والصحة لجلالتك.
Greetings, Mother.
تحياتي أمي.
At ease.
براحة.
Lord Ning,
اللورد نينغ،
I thought you wouldn't attend today.
اعتقدت أنك لن تحضر اليوم.
So you went to escort my mother instead.
لذلك ذهبت لمرافقة والدتي بدلا من ذلك.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
it's the Dragon Boat Festival.
إنه مهرجان قوارب التنين.
Ancient people prayed for safety
كان الناس القدماء يصلون من أجل السلامة
and blessings.
والبركات.
With everyone gathering here today,
مع تجمع الجميع هنا اليوم،
I'll join the fun.
سأنضم إلى المرح.
Since it's an auspicious occasion,
وبما أنها مناسبة ميمونة،
why are they
لماذا هم
punishing maids outside?
معاقبة الخادمات في الخارج؟
A maid suspected
خادمة مشتبه بها
a consort of hiding a pregnancy.
زوجة إخفاء الحمل.
Don't mind it, Mother.
لا يهمك يا أمي.
Mother,
الأم،
please take a seat.
من فضلك اجلس .
You manage countless state affairs
أنت تدير عددًا لا يحصى من شؤون الدولة
and are devoted to governance,
وهم مكرسون للحكم،
but
لكن
continuing the imperial lineage
استمرار السلالة الإمبراطورية
remains your foremost obligation.
يظل التزامك الأهم.
Only with thriving descendants
فقط مع الأحفاد المزدهرين
can the empire endure for millennia!
هل تستطيع الإمبراطورية أن تصمد لآلاف السنين!
- We heed Your Majesty's wisdom.
- نحن نستمع إلى حكمة جلالتك.
I beg your forgiveness.
أطلب منك السماح.
Consort Chun,
القرينة تشون،
what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
actually,
في الحقيقة،
I am pregnant.
أنا حامل.
The Imperial Hospital has recorded it,
وقد سجلها المستشفى الإمبراطوري،
but the physician said
ولكن الطبيب قال
I'm too weak,
أنا ضعيف جدا
with unstable fetus
مع الجنين غير المستقر
and a risk of miscarriage.
وخطر الإجهاض.
I couldn't bear to trouble Your Majesty with this worry.
لم أستطع أن أتحمل إزعاج جلالتك بهذا القلق.
Hence, my silence until now.
ومن هنا صمتي حتى الآن.
Rise, my love.
انهض يا حبيبي.
Consort Chun has served for years
لقد خدمت الزوجة تشون لسنوات
without conceiving.
بدون تصور.
Now, she's finally pregnant.
والآن أصبحت حاملاً أخيراً.
Truly cause for celebration!
سبب حقيقي للاحتفال!
- Congratulations on the royal heir.
- ألف مبروك على ولي العهد الملكي.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
since Consort Chun is pregnant,
بما أن الزوجة تشون حامل،
she shouldn't see blood.
لا ينبغي لها أن ترى الدم.
On such a joyous day, why not
في مثل هذا اليوم السعيد، لماذا لا؟
let the maid go
دع الخادمة تذهب
unpunished
دون عقاب
for good fortune?
من أجل الحظ السعيد؟
Lord Ning, you speak wisely.
يا سيد نينغ، أنت تتحدث بحكمة.
Suspend her flogging.
أوقفوا جلدها.
Thanks for your mercy on Jiuning's behalf.
شكرا على رحمتك نيابة عن جيونينج.
Rise, Noble Consort Xian.
انهضي يا زوجتك النبيلة شيان.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Consort Chun rendered great merit today.
لقد قدمت الزوجة تشون خدمة عظيمة اليوم.
Name your reward, my love.
سمّي مكافأتك يا حبيبتي.
I shall grant it generously.
سأمنحه بسخاء.
Your Majesty, your previous gifts
جلالتك، هداياك السابقة
already overflow my chambers.
لقد فاضت غرفتي بالفعل.
Instead,
بدلاً من،
may I request a companion?
هل يمكنني أن أطلب مرافق؟
Who?
من؟
Lady Shen.
السيدة شين.
We share kindred spirits
نحن نتشارك أرواحًا متقاربة
and often keep each other company,
وغالبا ما يبقون مع بعضهم البعض،
but her distant residence hinders visits.
لكن إقامتها البعيدة تعيق الزيارات.
If she could move to Chengxi Palace,
إذا استطاعت أن تنتقل إلى قصر تشنغشي،
we might better support each other,
ربما يمكننا أن ندعم بعضنا البعض بشكل أفضل،
alleviating my solitary days.
تخفيف أيام وحدتي.
Granted.
ممنوح.
Lady Shen
السيدة شين
shall live in Chengxi Palace's annex.
سوف يعيش في ملحق قصر تشنغشي.
Move there tomorrow.
انتقل هناك غدا.
Thank you, Your Majesty. Thank you, Your Highness.
شكراً لك يا جلالة الملك. شكراً لك يا سمو الأمير.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
Lady Shen has moved in.
انتقلت السيدة شين.
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي، صاحب السمو.
You fear me?
هل تخاف مني؟
No.
لا.
I wouldn't dare.
لا أجرؤ على ذلك.
To serve you
لخدمتك
is my greatest honor.
هو أعظم شرف لي.
You carry my child now.
أنت تحمل طفلي الآن.
How could I let fear distress you?
كيف يمكنني أن أسمح للخوف أن يزعجك؟
Thanks...
شكرًا...
Don't kneel so much.
لا تركع كثيرا
You'll harm the baby.
سوف تؤذي الطفل.
You did well this time.
لقد قمت بعمل جيد هذه المرة.
You not only revealed Lu Jiuning's scheme to me,
لم تكشف لي مخطط لو جيونينج فحسب،
but also enacted that brilliant charade,
بل قاموا أيضًا بتمثيل تلك المسرحية الهزلية الرائعة،
taking away Noble Consort Xian's seal.
إزالة ختم الزوجة النبيلة شيان.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Once you deliver the child,
بمجرد أن تولد الطفل،
you'll receive abundant rewards.
سوف تحصل على مكافآت وفيرة.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Go settle down.
اذهب واستقر.
I'll take my leave.
سوف آخذ إجازتي.
This crucial matter is finally settled.
لقد تمت تسوية هذه المسألة الحاسمة أخيرا.
My brother has secretly taken control of Lady Shen's family.
لقد تولى أخي السيطرة على عائلة السيدة شين سراً.
Inform him
أبلغه
that after our success,
أنه بعد نجاحنا،
none shall be spared.
لن يسلم أحد.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموك.
Moreover,
علاوة على ذلك،
tell Physician Zhang to check my pulse regularly
أخبر الطبيب تشانغ بفحص نبضي بانتظام
and prescribe prenatal remedies.
ووصف العلاجات قبل الولادة.
Don't let anyone notice
لا تدع أحدا يلاحظ
that I'm not truly pregnant.
أنني لست حاملاً حقًا.
Yes.
نعم.
Serves her right.
إنها تستحق ذلك.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Stay away.
ابقى بعيدا.
Bad luck.
سوء الحظ.
Hurry, let's go.
اسرع دعنا نذهب.
Lu Jiuning,
لو جيونينج,
you publicly slandered Consort Chun,
لقد قمت بتشويه سمعة قرينتك تشون علنًا،
yet managed to escape death.
ولكن تمكن من الهروب من الموت.
You got lucky this time.
لقد كنت محظوظا هذه المرة.
Didn't we agree
ألم نتفق
to expose Consort Chun's schemes?
لفضح مخططات الزوجة تشون؟
Why did you go back on your word?
لماذا تراجعت عن كلمتك؟
Save your breath.
أنقذ أنفاسك.
Are you the only clever one?
هل أنت الذكي الوحيد؟
Consort Chun knew you approached me with malicious intentions,
لقد عرفت الزوجة تشون أنك اقتربت مني بنوايا خبيثة،
so she played along with your scheme
لذلك لعبت مع خطتك
to eliminate you,
للقضاء عليك
and simultaneously
وفي نفس الوقت
drag Noble Consort Xian down with you.
اسحب النبيلة الزوجة شيان معك إلى الأسفل.
To challenge Consort Chun,
لتحدي القرينة تشون،
you're too inexperienced.
أنت عديم الخبرة للغاية.
Only by following
فقط من خلال المتابعة
the noble Consort Chun
النبيلة كونسورت تشون
will I find the proper path.
هل سأجد الطريق الصحيح؟
You're beyond cure
أنت لا يمكن علاجك
and utterly hopeless.
ويائس تماما.
You'd rather stake everything
كنت تفضل أن تراهن بكل شيء
on an uncertain future
حول مستقبل غير مؤكد
than face the reality.
من مواجهة الواقع.
What utter foolishness!
يا له من حماقة مطلقة!
You'll regret this.
سوف تندم على هذا.
This world is rigidly stratified,
هذا العالم مقسم إلى طبقات صارمة،
with clear hierarchies.
مع التسلسل الهرمي الواضح.
The immense power and wealth
القوة والثروة الهائلة
are beyond anything we could earn in a lifetime.
إنها تفوق أي شيء يمكننا كسبه في حياتنا.
But I...
ولكن انا...
As long as I deliver this child,
طالما أني سأنجب هذا الطفل،
I'll rise above all others.
سأرتفع فوق كل الآخرين.
From then on,
ومنذ ذلك الحين،
my family
عائلتي
will never be trampled underfoot again.
لن يتم دهسه تحت الأقدام مرة أخرى.
Who wouldn't be tempted by this?
من لا يغريه هذا؟
From this moment,
من هذه اللحظة،
your life starts its countdown.
حياتك تبدأ العد التنازلي.
We'll meet again in the next life.
سوف نلتقي مرة أخرى في الحياة القادمة.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
We'll see about that.
سوف نرى ذلك.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
Lady Shen struck Lu Jiuning today.
السيدة شين ضربت لو جيونينج اليوم.
They've completely fallen out.
لقد سقطوا تماما.
Lady Shen
السيدة شين
is indeed a status-seeking opportunist.
إنه في الواقع انتهازي يبحث عن المكانة.
She followed your instructions,
لقد اتبعت تعليماتك،
nearly finishing off Lu Jiuning.
كاد أن ينهي لو جيونينج.
You truly
انت حقا
remain several steps ahead.
تظل عدة خطوات للأمام.
When people have ambitions,
عندما يكون للناس طموحات،
they become easier to manipulate.
يصبح من السهل التعامل معهم.
You're truly brilliant.
أنت رائع حقا.
Lu Jiuning relied on her petty cleverness
اعتمدت لو جيونينج على ذكائها البسيط
and caused trouble.
وتسبب في مشاكل.
She is in no position to stir anything up now.
إنها ليست في وضع يسمح لها بإثارة أي شيء الآن.
She is just a maid.
إنها مجرد خادمة.
Crushing her is much easier.
سحقها أسهل بكثير.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموك.
Everything looks fine.
كل شيء يبدو جيدا.
Chief Physician Zhang.
الطبيب الرئيسي تشانغ.
Yes.
نعم.
I entrust my pregnancy to your care.
أضع حملي تحت رعايتك.
Keep Imperial Hospital's records
الاحتفاظ بسجلات مستشفى إمبريال
straight.
مستقيم.
Don't let anything slip.
لا تدع أي شيء يفلت من يديك.
Rest assured, Your Highness.
اطمئن يا صاحب السمو.
Your prenatal records
سجلاتك قبل الولادة
will mirror Lady Shen's
سوف تعكس السيدة شين
actual condition.
الحالة الفعلية.
Nothing will go wrong.
لن يحدث أي خطأ.
Good.
جيد.
Now, we'll await
الآن سوف ننتظر
Lady Shen
السيدة شين
to deliver a healthy prince for me.
لتسليم لي أميرًا سليمًا.
You two, clean this place up properly.
يجب عليكما تنظيف هذا المكان جيدًا.
- Yes.
- نعم.
How dare she come?
كيف تجرؤ على المجيء؟
Xiaotao,
شياو تاو
here.
هنا.
We wouldn't dare trouble you.
نحن لا نجرؤ على إزعاجك.
Jiuning,
جيونينج،
don't take it personally.
لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل شخصي.
Yunxiang,
يون شيانغ،
we all had our salaries suspended for a year.
لقد تم تعليق رواتبنا جميعًا لمدة عام.
How dare you approach this jinx?
كيف تجرؤ على الاقتراب من هذا النحس؟
Exactly!
بالضبط!
Jiuning once saved my life when I was in danger.
لقد أنقذني جيونينج ذات مرة عندما كنت في خطر.
Don't treat her this way.
لا تعاملها بهذه الطريقة
Yunxiang,
يون شيانغ،
she slandered Consort Chun like mad that day,
لقد شوهت سمعة الزوجة تشون بشدة في ذلك اليوم،
making our salaries suspended.
مما أدى إلى تعليق رواتبنا.
It even cost Her Highness the Phoenix Seal.
حتى أنها كلفت صاحبة السمو ختم الفينيق.
Today,
اليوم،
she's the sinner of Yongxiu Palace,
إنها خاطئة قصر يونغشيو،
our collective enemy!
عدونا الجماعي!
- Exactly! - She dares show up?
- بالضبط! - هل تجرؤ على الظهور؟
You jinx! You're good for nothing!
يا لك من نحس! أنت لا تصلح لأي شيء!
- Useless one! - Exactly!
- عديم الفائدة! - بالضبط!
- What do you take us for? - Your fault!
- ماذا تظننا؟ - خطؤك!
- All because of her! - Yunxiang,
- كل هذا بفضلها! - يون شيانغ،
you were right.
لقد كنت على حق.
She joined Yongxiu Palace
انضمت إلى قصر يونغشيو
with ulterior motives.
بدوافع خفية.
She aimed to use Her Highness
لقد كانت تهدف إلى استخدام صاحبة السمو
against Consort Chun.
ضد الزوجة تشون.
- That's right!
- هذا صحيح!
What's this argument about?
ما هو هذا الجدل حول؟
What crime is it to disturb Her Highness?
ما هي الجريمة التي تزعج صاحبة السمو؟
Jiuning, Her Highness let you come in.
جيونينج، صاحبة السمو سمحت لك بالدخول.
Yes.
نعم.
Do you confess?
هل تعترف؟
Jiuning,
جيونينج،
Her Highness warned you not to act rashly.
لقد حذرتك صاحبة السمو من التصرف بتهور.
By slandering a consort publicly,
من خلال التشهير بزوجته علنًا،
you dragged her into trouble
لقد جررتها إلى المتاعب
and got her confined.
وتم حبسها.
Have you no remorse?
هل ليس لديك ندم؟
Consort Chun abuses power
الزوجة تشون تسيء استخدام السلطة
and takes lives lightly
ويأخذ الأرواح باستخفاف
I'll avenge Wan'er
سأنتقم لوان إير
and stop her
وأوقفها
from harming innocents.
من إيذاء الأبرياء.
I miscalculated this time.
لقد أخطأت في حساباتي هذه المرة.
But even with her immense power,
ولكن حتى مع قوتها الهائلة،
as long as I am alive,
ما دمت على قيد الحياة،
I'll fight her to the end.
سأقاتلها حتى النهاية.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
If you remain arrogant
إذا بقيت متغطرسًا
and reckless,
ومتهورة
you'll not only fail to avenge Wan'er,
لن تفشل في الانتقام لوان إير فحسب،
but also lose your own life!
بل وتخسر ​​حياتك أيضًا!
Hasn't this bloody lesson taught you anything?
ألم يعلمك هذا الدرس اللعين أي شيء؟
What are you thinking?
ماذا تفكر؟
They're right.
إنهم على حق.
I joined Yongxiu Palace
انضممت إلى قصر يونغشيو
just to use you
فقط لاستخدامك
against Consort Chun.
ضد الزوجة تشون.
Now, I've brought ruin upon Yongxiu Palace.
الآن، لقد جلبت الخراب على قصر يونغشيو.
I've failed you.
لقد خذلتك.
I beg your permission to leave Yongxiu Palace.
أطلب الإذن منك لمغادرة قصر يونغشيو.
You...
أنت...
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
Yongxiu Palace
قصر يونغ شيو
isn't some place you enter and leave at will!
ليس هناك مكان تدخله وتخرج منه متى شئت!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Let her go.
اسمح لها أن تذهب.
Once you leave,
بمجرد مغادرتك،
never return.
لن تعود أبدًا.
Thank you,
شكرًا لك،
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.